

Anish George Project Manager|Scrum Master|Agile CoachIIT Service Deliveryl

anishgeo@gmail.com 🔀

+91-9847546003

Trivandrum, India

https://linkedin.com/in/anish-george-a2491816 in

Project management professional with global experience in Project & Product management, System Design and Development. On-site project management experience in Middle East and Asia-Pac regions - Australia , New Zealand & UAE. Proficient in Traditional , Agile -Scrum, DevOps methodologies. Always keep a flare towards technology and can translate business strategies to viable IT solutions.

SKILLS

Project management		РМО	Ser	vice Delivery	Transition	Management	MSP 2016
Agile / Scrum	rum Matrices Reporting		esign	ITIL	Risk Man	agement	РМР
Infrastructure Build SaFe		e Agile	Stakeholder Mana		agement	Budgeting and Costing	

VISA

Australian Permanent Residency Holder - PR # 0049542628682 , looking forward to migrate to NSW

CERTIFICATIONS

PMP® (12/2011 - 12/2020) Project Management Professional from PMI,USA

CSM® (06/2012 - 06/2020) Certified Scrum Master from Scrum Alliance

ITIL® Foundation (03/2015 - Present) AXELOS - Global Best Practice

Certified SAFe® Practitioner (05/2017 - 06/2019) Scaled Agile, USA

PRINCE2® - Foundation & Practitioner (02/2018 – 09/2021) AXFLOS - Global Best Practice

WORK EXPERIENCE

Assistant Director (Project Manager) - Global Tax IT & GDS IT Service Delivery

Project Manager, PMO Manager, Scrum Master, IT Service Delivery, Mentor and Coach - PMO On boarding

EY - Ernst & Young

11/2011 - Present

GDS (Global Delivery Services) Kerala, India

Roles & Responsibilities

Project Management Centre of Excellence (CoE) - Played significant role in executing a blue print in elevating GDS (Global Delivery Services) Kerala centre as a PM CoE. 15 % Y-o-Y PM capacity increase achieved since this initiative.

Demand Management - Engaged with Global Tax & GDS IT services leadership in forecasting program / project demands , Drove estimation and finalize on service line IT project budgets.

Demand Validation - Validate demands for technology stack involving solution and infra architects. Niche technologies like mobility, cloud adoption and analytic are given priorities aligning to EY SMAC strategy.

Project Management - Managed Global Tax IT and GDS (Global Delivery Services) projects ranging from 0.5 to 2 million USD with a strong focus on EY vision 2020+. Adopted a business case driven project execution approach with a commitment to adhere scope, cost and time line.

Project Report and statistics - Deliver clear and concise weekly & steering committee reports and dashboards.

Risk Management - Always keep a keen eye on project risks and issues. Risk reporting and actioning are routines.

Resource Management – Accountable team owner responsible to resource utilization , skill augmentation and delivery commitments. Ensured right resource mix to bring down project cost and removes technical and soft skill impediments through coaching and mentoring. Met resource utilization targets of over 90% standard utilization.

Stakeholder Management – Managed customer expectations on project deliverables through proper stakeholder communication and implementing an effective system of project governance.

Process and project monitoring – Championed process improvement initiatives and implement best practices. Project compliance monitored using stage gate reviews for quality and optimal delivery.

Tool and Process adoption - Drove the adoption of tools and best practices for efficient, rapid, and predictable project execution using relevant software tools and practices like Agile & SCRUM.

Transition & Change management - Performed transition, change and vendor management process.

Develop and Implement standards for training of project managers

WORK EXPERIENCE

Project Manager

Cognizant

01/2011 - 11/2011

Project Manager

Roles & Responsibilities



- Project Phoenix Managed the implementation of commercial off the shelf vendor Asset management solution across cognizant location. The role out aimed at a huge cost saving in terms of rationalizing asset usage and bring down the Hardware and software licence usage.
- Project Initiation and Baselines Key responsibilities include finalize and procure sign off on MSA & SOW. Detail the project charter, project plan and staff augmentation from both vendor and internal resources.
- Implement Controls Project was run under the direct supervision of Cognizant leadership and hence strived to enforce stringent budget control measures , peruse vendor invoices and engaged stakeholders efficiently.
- Benefits Management Kept financial objectives on top priority by budget forecasting and variance analysis. Facilitated process
 workshops and technical interface sessions to reduce functional gap and mitigate risks.
- Migration Strategy Worked out product migration and roll out strategy for a staggered cut over.

Project Manager

IBS Software Services (Qantas Airways - Australia)

09/2009 - 12/2010

Sydney, Australia

On-site Project Manager , Transition , Change and Cut over Manager , Air cargo domain specialist

Roles & Responsibilities

- Migration iCargo Product roll out On site product implementation manager for rolling out Air cargo reservation module across global Qantas network airports.
- Managed product fit / gap process ,finalize scope , prepare SOW & charter and baseline milestone dates.
- Monitored project P&L, Contractual obligations were met and milestones were invoiced successfully.
- Collaborated efficiently in a multi vendor delivery model.
- Supervised quality assurance phases like site, factory, integration, user and operation acceptance testing.
- Track project progress diligently and produce weekly reports WSR and steering committee reports.
- Ensured business continuity with the account and additional 15 % revenue generated through change request.
- Drove the feasibility study on e-Freight & mobility initiatives.

Product Manager, On-Site Product implementation manager

IBS Software Services (Air New Zealand - New Zealand)

06/2005 - 06/2009

Auckland, New Zealand

On-site Project Manager , Transition , Change and Cut over Manager , Air cargo domain specialist Roles & Responsibilities

- Air cargo domain consultant defining the future state process with subject matter experts.
- Prepare process maps to replace the legacy system with web based product solution.
- Managed product RFP, costing & contract negotiation phases.
- Executed product Fit/Gap phase, scope finalization, SOW and project schedule.
- Maintained strong reporting on project progress and identified project risks.
- Evaluate change requests with regards to costs, scope and schedule.
- Manage financial statements, stakeholder engagements and escalations.

Project Lead, Software engineer IBS Software Services (Emirates - United Arab Emirates)

12/2003 - 05/2005

Dubai.United Arab Emirates (UAE)

On-site Project Lead , Design & Development

– Roles & Responsibilities

- Managed design & development of core air cargo modules for Emirates and Dnata cargo.
- Evangelised software and design patterns contributing to sturdy code base and reduce development cycle time.
- User acceptance, site acceptance and system integration testing.
- Offshore and on site support for product roll out.
- Managed product transition, both technical and functional with business.

Page 2 of 3

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer IBS Software Services

05/2001 - 11/2003

Trivandrum ,India

Software engineer , Team Lead & Test Lead

- Role & Responsibilities
- Software developer Technologies using Java , JSP, J2EE , Oracle SQL. Developed WBS and derived estimation. Lead teams in project and product development environments.
- System design High level and Low level design, Model systems using problem domain concepts with IBM design tool. Involved in design review sessions. Contributed in deriving a software framework and reduce development effort by 20%.
- Business Analysis Perform requirements elicitation sessions and produce specification documents as RSD, supplementary specification, integration specification and user interface documents. Received early exposure to discuss with varied levels of business stakeholders from various geographies.
- Test Lead Ensured system quality through unit, module, system and integration testing. Guided business on user acceptance testing. Delivered value through test automation and reporting.
- Off Shore product roll out support Application engineering support in issue analysis and resolution as part of L4 support model.

IT SKILLS & EXPERTISE

-Software/Packages

-os

- Programming Languages / frameworks

-Infrastructure build out

DevOps essential Tools

-Web / App /DB Servers

MS Project 2016, 2013, MS Office , Share point , PPM , JIRA

Windows, Linux kernel

JS , Java , Struts , JSP , J2EE , Oracle ,Web technologies On Premise IT Infrastructure build and Microsoft Azure cloud

Docker, Jenkins, Maven, Git, SVN

Tomcat, Web Logic, Windows IIS, Oracle

ACCOLADES

- Project Management Champion @ EY- On board aspiring internal and lateral entry managers through PM on-boarding programme
- Extra miler Rockers award @ EY for building high performing project team FY 2013
- Orange Belt member for driving business process improvement @ EY from GDS Operations IT Services
- Process Compliance award @ EY from Centre Quality Team for VoC 3.0 project
- Feather on the cap award @ EY for delivering a memorable Project Management Day FY 2015
- Certificate of Excellence from Qantas Airways for rolling out Air Cargo reservation suite of products across network centres.
- Certificate of Excellence for committed project delivery from Emirate Airlines for projects NOMAD & Chameleon
- Functional Area Representative in software design and development @ IBS Software services in achieving CMM level 5.

EDUCATION

- Bachelor in Technology (B.Tech) in Mechanical Engineering from College of Engineering, Trivandrum, Kerala, India.
- First class with Distinction (80.62 %) and featured among top 5 ranks.